[MUSIC]
Hello and thank you for joining.
I'm Andrei Panko and I
will be doing demos for you.
In this release, we
continue our investment in
warehouse and inventory management areas,
both done by internal R&D team,
but I also would like to
mention the community contributions.
Many features are added
by community members via GitHub,
and you can find all
details in the release notes entries,
including text
descriptions and screenshots.
But for some features,
I would like to do demos,
and we will be doing demos
for some warehouse improvements.
In the release notes, you might find
these articles and
probably the third one is
the most obvious one
to understand what it's doing.
For others, you might be curious.
Let's do demo and get some clarity.
Now, in Business Central,
let's start by exploring location cards.
Let's go to the location list,
find the favorite
silver location which is
added by Contoso Demo Data app here,
and explore what we have.
The biggest changes we
can notice in the warehouse tab,
you can still see
the required receipt ship put
away and pick toggles are there,
but now they are limited only to purchase
sales, service, and transfer operations,
while internal
operations such as production,
assembly, and jobs
got all configuration options,
and it's not toggles,
but actual
drop-downs with different options
where you can
select various combinations.
For example, you can disable
warehouse handling
or have a different flavors.
What I did here, I
configured all different options.
For example, for sales orders,
I will be doing shipments,
but receiving will be done via put away.
In production, I don't
want to use any warehouse handling
because I will be
using movement worksheet
to transfer stuff out of warehouse.
Then I have a warehouse pick in
some scenarios and
inventory picks for jobs.
Let's explore in action.
But before that, I will
scroll down to the bin policy tab.
This tab still has the same fields,
or almost the same fields,
but with each release,
more of them are getting available
to the basic warehouse configurations.
You don't need to use
directed pick and put away
to benefit from special equipment,
bin capacity policy, or warehouse class,
which were added in the previous release.
Or now you can
also use put away templates
when assigning bins
where items should be located,
or bin ranking.
Now put away template is available.
And if you decided
not to use default bin,
which was available before,
but switch to put away template,
you can pick default one.
All right, let's
go to different documents
and see how it works.
Let's start by purchase orders.
I will find my order.
And as you remember,
I decided to use inventory putaways.
So I have two items here,
and let's create inventory put away.
Okay.
All good.
Now navigate to create a document.
Couple of clicks and we're here.
What do we see?
We see that for one item,
we received three
lines instead of one in the past,
which would be default bin.
And for the last
one, we received nothing.
Why?
Because each item is using,
configured to use
different put away templates.
And I decided to use
standard template for item number one.
But for put away for another item,
I decided to try something different.
Let me show you details of this template,
how they're configured.
So the standard one,
which is also included into the product
and part of the Contoso demo data,
it's pretty complicated.
And it tries, first of all,
fill up bins which
already contains items.
And if it fails,
then it tries to find the next best bin
accordingly to the rules.
But I also have a simplified scenario.
When I allow system to propose bins only,
if these bins already contain some stock.
And if not, it stops.
That's why we have a different result.
For example, first item we needed 80,
but if you take a
look at the bin content list,
we can see that this
item is already available
in the warehouse.
It's available in couple of bins
and they favor some quantity,
but they also have
some max quantity restrictions.
So system just added
missing quantities there.
And for remaining, it
finds the best bin it could
using bin ranking.
The last one,
no, this item is not available currently.
So we cannot find the existing bin.
That's why we
decided to delegate this work to
warehouse employee who
will decide where to store this item
in specific scenario.
So you can use different approaches.
All right, so I
selected the bin which fits best,
but also I noticed that instead of 80,
I received 85.
So let's add over received quantity.
Yeah, over received
quantity is now also available
in the inventory put away
in addition to the house receives before.
So now you are not
restricted at least by this parameter
on which document to use.
All right, that was a small side story.
Now we go to the wallet center
and now we will explore sales orders.
So we have sales order and let's create
a warehouse shipment.
Okay, warehouse shipment created.
It does not require me to create pick
because it configured so,
so I can just go and ship stuff
if I have inventory available.
Let's go to different document.
And in this case, it
will be release production order.
Production orders
configured to use warehouse picks.
Let's click warehouse pick.
Okay.
And it was created.
Now let's navigate to create a pick
and explore what is there.
Oh, so many lines, why?
Why?
We need the 30 and they are unfortunately
not available in a single bin.
It's available in
three different bins, 10 in each.
And these bins have a different ranking.
So system, that's
why they have a special code
so it will be easier to illustrate.
But the highest
ranking, 30 is on this bin,
then medium and the lowest in this bin.
And system proposed
to do picking accordingly.
First, from bin with the highest trend
regardless of its
code, then the next one,
the final one.
So actually picking by ranking
is also available with inventory picks.
Let's explore.
This functionality
or this type of picking
is enabled for jobs as
we configured our location.
Let's open the job card.
We can see multiple job tasks
and choose create inventory pick.
We need to
activate create inventory pick.
Also, I would like
to add a separate filter
job task line
because I would like to limit
the scope of create
pick only two components
listed under first job task
because it's a long project
and probably I
don't need to get inventory
for other task, for other milestones.
I can also use a date.
This capability,
this filtering capabilities
were added in the previous release
but I think it
makes sense to show it here.
Okay, I received, I
created one inventory pick.
Let's navigate.
And open this pick.
The same story.
So we are picking
from three different bins
because it is available there.
So the same story about picking first
from the bin with the highest rank
because our location configured this way.
All right.
So, picking by ranking is available
in both workhouse and inventory pick.
Let's go to, for example, assembly order
and do some additional check.
In this case, assembly
order requires warehouse picking.
I will create a warehouse pick.
I click okay.
And I got this nothing to handle error
which is not really useful.
So, how do we deal
with it in basic workhouse?
Let me demonstrate you something
but first I will show you
one of my favorite client features
added into this release.
It's a show details
which allows me to
navigate directly to the cart.
Let me scroll down and
you can see that always create
pick client is
disabled, but it is available
even for basic workhouse configurations.
I will activate it.
And now when I
click create warehouse pick,
I got pick created.
And if you will open this pick,
we can see that it has
a take and place instruction
and bin code is empty.
Of course, system
didn't find the item to find
but we know that it is available.
And it is available in the bin
which is for some
reason marked as dedicated.
But I know that I
want to take this stuff here.
So, I'm making decision and I'm accepting
to take stuff from this bin code.
So, at least I was able to unblock myself
and move further.
Let's register it.
All good.
Available inventory.
All right.
That was for basic workhouse
but it is also
transition to the next topic
because nothing to handle
error is displayed quite often
in our, as we can
see now it's elementary.
Let's see and it's
not easy to troubleshoot.
And we did some improvement,
mainly focus it for
locations with directed pick
and put away configuration enabled.
Let's take a look.
I have multiple, actually two.
I have two workhouse
shipments created in a white location
and let's open it and click create pick.
Yeah.
Not very useful.
Not very useful but then
I will try to create pick again
and in this case I will
activate the short summary toggle.
It also identifies you
that it's only for directed put away
and pick mode.
So, do not try it
on other configurations.
And what do we see here?
We get the same
error message, it's on top
but we also receive additional details.
We got the full troubleshooting window
where we have multiple,
conceptually place for multiple lines.
In this case I'm
dealing with only one item
that's why I have one line.
And I see quantity
which I wanted to pick.
I needed one.
And how many I managed to handle?
Nothing.
Why?
This information we
can get from the summary part
which is added here.
Because pickable quantity is zero.
In the advanced workhouse
with directed put away and pick
the workhouse is
split into different zones
and only one of them contains items
which can be picked for shipment
or for example for future consumption.
So that's called pickable one.
And how do we calculate them?
You can see that in
general in workhouse I have 10 items.
I can explore ledger
entries that not super useful
but I can go and explore bin content.
It will also show me
how these 10 are distributed.
And yes, I have a lot in
my workhouse in different bins.
Nine of them pieces
are in the pickable bins
but unfortunately it is
either blocked or dedicated.
Means it has a very
specific purpose and not for picking
or both and dedicated and blocked.
And I also have one
thing, one piece outstanding
in the receive bin.
So it's very easy
for me to get unblocked.
I need to find the put
away document and process it.
For some reason it was not processed
but at least I know whom to ask for help
with getting unblocked.
Before it was more
complicated to troubleshoot
now it is shorter.
What about more complicated scenarios?
Of course I have them.
Let's scroll to the
different workhouse shipment.
It has two items,
different types of items
to demonstrate different scenarios.
Let's click create pick.
And I already know that
I would like to show summary.
Okay, in this situation
you can see that for the first line
we managed to pick
zero but for the second line
something can be picked.
But let's take a look at the details.
First of all, here
it's interesting to notice
that pickable bins,
actually we have something.
If I was drill down I can
get bin content on pickable bins.
Where dedicated toggle is disabled
and there is no
blocking of outbound movements.
So this is very good
bin and it has some quantity
which theoretically could be picked.
But, but.
This item has item tracking.
If I scroll down I can see that yeah,
this item has item tracking defined.
And this specific item
has serial number information card
with blocked field enabled.
So basically I cannot use
this item because it's blocked.
And I get this
information again right here.
So I just need to find this item,
figure it out why it is blocked,
maybe unblock it if
necessary and also unblock myself.
Let's take a look at the next line.
This is more complicated scenario
because now it
has, it involves reservation
and reservation has some impact.
So what do we want?
We want to pick four.
And how many do we have in warehouse?
Four.
So kind of like what's the problem?
Yeah.
The problem is that
there are some other orders
which also needs to be
picked, shipped, consumed, et cetera.
And they have a high priority.
Why?
Because they are reserved.
So this one is not reserved.
So it has no less priorities than others.
So in this case,
we should not make orders
with high priority, which are reserved.
Should not make them impossible to ship.
It's okay to make it
difficult to ship, but not impossible.
Let me explain.
So while we have a
total quantity in warehouse 10,
four are impeccable bins,
which can be picked, shipped right away.
But we also have six somewhere else.
Where do we have them?
We have four
impeccable bins, as we already know,
but we also have four in the putaway bin.
So it's like a different storage,
which requires movement if necessary.
So we consider this
quantity to be something
which we need to
compare with reservations.
So eight is potentially can be used.
Yeah, it requires
some additional actions.
For example, if it's in
putaway, it's in received bins,
and you need to process putaway.
If it's in bulk storage bin,
you need to move it into pickable bins,
but it can be done.
That's why it is okay to take stuff
from the pickable
bin for some other bins,
unless we still have
something in the warehouse
which can be shipped for reserve.
So what about reservation situation?
Yeah, we reserved eight.
Eight, we reserved for this sales order,
which sounds like,
okay, then 100% is reserved.
Not really, not really.
Because out of this eight reserved,
we already picked.
So it means this stuff is
already moved to the shipping bin.
And so it can be deducted.
So out of this eight, we can deduct two
which are already prepared for shipping.
It's not that trivial, I understand.
Stay with me.
But we have also two
tips which try to explain
how the stuff is calculated.
So for example, let's
go to the last one, impact.
And here we explain that potentially,
shipable from warehouse is eight.
It's like
everything which is in warehouse
except in the shipment bin,
because shipment bin or dedicated bin,
which is already
almost loaded to the truck.
So forget about them.
But potentially,
shipable eight, okay, here.
But we also have reservation,
except reservations
which are already shipped.
So reservation,
then we compare these two.
And this delta is what we can take
for other non-reserved orders.
So in this case, the delta is two.
So that's why we're
adjusting pickable quantity
from four to two.
And this is how quantity is defined.
I have the same text
written for in the release node.
And we're also, of
course, updating the documentation.
Probably with more fancy schemas.
All right, so in this case, I have two.
So system already created pick for two.
How can I get unblocked
if I really, really
need to pick this stuff?
So I have two options.
I either reserve this sales order,
then reserve against reserve.
There is no prioritization conflict.
So this one can be processed directly.
Or I will go and cancel reservation.
Because I decided that it is okay to do.
We will buy more stuff
later for this specific order.
It is okay.
We explored, we met from.
Now I can close this
window and run create pick again.
Let's activate it again.
For the second round,
you can see that the first line
still nothing
changed because we still blocked.
And we didn't take any action.
But the second line, we
had two remaining to be picked.
And they can be picked.
So all good with this line.
So what we figured
it out in this demonstration
that first of all, now you
do not need to use directed pick
if the customer or user requires
some workhouse capabilities.
First of all, you can implement it
for different departments individually.
Like, okay, let's
start with a shipping team
because they are most ready
and do not touch
manufacturing or jobs, et cetera.
Or you can use different policies.
For example, here we're using shipping,
here we're inventory picks, et cetera.
And different combinations, all good.
And also, even if
we're using the basic workhouse,
we still can benefit
from advanced capabilities
like put away
templates, picking by ranking,
and also allow or do
not allow creation of lines
in pick and put away documents
if there are some problems.
Means we allow or do not allow
workhouse employee or workhouse manager
to solve problems by themselves.
So giving them some control.
Also, we have an ability
to receive more than ordered,
also using inventory put away
together with direct
update of purchase document
or workhouse receipt.
This unblocks you and
doesn't impact your decision
about which process you need to use
because all of
them supporting overreceive.
And if you decided
to use directed put away
and pick warehouses,
now you need to
spend dramatically less time
analyzing the nothing to handle situation
because you can get more insights
from the special troubleshooting window
which gives you all details right away.
So if you're
interested in workhouse session,
probably you're also
interested in another technology
like it's barcode scanning capabilities.
And we have something to present for you.
So take a look at the
session about mobile apps.
Also take a look at the
session reservation worksheet
and fulfillment suggestions.
It's about reservation and inventory.
So it also might be interesting.
I would like also to
mention the list of valuable resources.
Start with submit your ideas
if you have something to
say about missing functionality,
both there and ideas really matters.
We have a more detailed
discussion in a different forum.
It's also available for partners.
It's a first link in
this resource, it's Yammer.
Feel free to join and
participate in the design discussions
or get information about like what's
and how it getting to be implemented.
And because it's only a
few out of our different links,
we have one link to link them all.
It's a BC all, aka.ms.
Go there, explore what
you have, what we have there.
And so thank you and let's stay in touch.
Join Yammer, let's talk there.